( telephone ringing )
- Hello ? - ( the voice ) Hello .
- Uh , yes ? - Who is this ?
- Who are you calling ? - Who am I speaking to ?
( scoffs ) Wrong number . ( beep )
- Who was that ? - Oh , nobody .
- Did you pick a movie ? - Yeah . We 're gonna go scary .
- " Saw 4 . " - Ugh . I saw that in theaters .
It sucks . It 's not scary , it 's gross .
I hate all that torture-porn shit .
( chuckles ) How do you really feel ?
Well , I like Jigsaw . I think he kills people very creatively .
But you don 't give a shit who dies ' cause there 's no character development .
There 's just body parts ripping and blood spewing . Blah .
- Who do you keep texting ? - I have a Facebook stalker .
- He keeps leaving me messages . - Yeah , like what ?
Just stuff . Like , " Hey , what 's up ? You 're hot . I wanna kill you . "
So delete him .
I did , but he hacked his way back in .
So report him .
He 's really hot , though . You wanna see ?
That 's Channing Tatum .
It is not . Is it ?
Yeah , from his Abercrombie days . You are being punk 'd .
( telephone rings )
- Hello ? - ( the voice ) Who is this ?
The more impatient version of the person you just spoke to .
I 'm sorry . You don 't have to be a bitch about it .
No , of course I don 't . Eat me .
You hang up on me and I 'll cut through your neck until I feel bone !
- Who is it ? - It 's for you .
- Hello ? - Who 's this ?
It 's Trudie . Who 's this ?
This is the last person you 're ever gonna see alive .
It 's a prank . Hang up .
( beep ) Why 'd you hand the phone to me ?
You 're the one with the stalker . Are the doors locked ?
Don 't freak out .
( telephone rings )
Let it ring .
( beep )
( cell phone vibrates )
It 's from stalker boy .
He said , " Answer the phone . "
( sighs ) For God 's sake . It 's a joke , Trudie .
It 's probably Lexi or Karen . Where are you going ?
To make sure the front door is locked .
( doorbell rings , both scream )
No . Don 't open it .
You 're overreacting . ( scoffs )
It 's a joke , Trudie , okay ? Somebody made a dummy profile .
- They 're just trying to scare you . - Wait .
( loudly ) Who is it ?
I said , who is it ?
Let 's call the cops .
( cell phone vibrates )
" I dare you to open the door . "
No , Sherrie . Don 't .
No , don 't , I 'm scared .
Hey , it could be anyone that we know .
Lisa , Bailey , Wayne ,
or the hopeful long shot , Channing Tatum .
- There 's nobody out here . - ( sighs softly )
( cell phone vibrates )
What does it say ?
It says , " I 'm not outside . I 'm right beside you . "
( screams ) Trudie !
Trudie ... oh , my God .
( screams )
( gasping )
( woman screams )
Fucking kidding me ?
What ?
That was so fucking stupid . Pure horseshit .
The death of horror right here in front of us .
I jumped . Scared me .
A fucking Facebook killer ? You 're kidding me , right ?
I guess now it would be Twitter . That 'd make more sense .
A bunch of articulate teens sit around and deconstruct horror movies
until Ghostface kills them one by one ?
It 's been done to death ,
the whole self-aware , post-modern meta shit .
Stick a fork in 1996 already .
I like the " Stab " movies . They 're scarier .
It 's not aliens or zombies or little Asian ghost girls .
There 's something real about a guy with a knife who just ...
snaps .
It could really happen .
I can 't do it . These sequels don 't know when to stop .
They just keep recycling the same shit .
Even the opening scene .
There 's always some random girl who gets a call
that undoubtedly ends up getting her killed .
It 's all so predictable . There 's no element of surprise .
You can see everything coming !
Aah ! ( gasps softly )
- ( gasps ) - Did that surprise you ?
Why ?
- Because you talk too much . - Agh !
Now shut the fuck up and watch the movie .
( chokes wetly )
( woman screams )
Oh , my God , I love it .
I 've seen it five times , and it still gets me every time .
You 're kidding . I don 't get it .
( TV shuts off )
Okay . It 's like " The Twilight Zone . "
" Twilight Zone " ? A movie within a movie .
I get that . But it 's illogical .
It begs the question that if the beginning of " Stab 7 " is " Stab 6 , "
then is the beginning of " Stab 6 " " Stab 5 " ?
And , if so , what is " Stab 4 " about ?
- You 're over-thinking it . - Am I ?
Or did whoever make it just under-think it ?
There 's a reason I don 't watch these movies .
I can 't believe you haven 't seen them . We live in Woodsboro .
That has nothing to do with Woodsboro .
I ... I thought you said " Stab " was based on true stories .
The first three , the original trilogy , is based off of Sidney Prescott ,
but then she threatened to sue them if they used her story ,
so then they just started making stuff up .
" Stab 5 " has time travel , which is by far the worst .
Don 't we hear enough about this story every year ?
At least Woodsboro 's known for something .
( faint rattle ) Did you hear that ?
Uh ... .
No , I didn 't hear anything .
I did .
Jenny ?
- Don 't try to scare me . - I 'm not trying to scare you .
- You do it all the time . - No , I don 't .
- Where are you going ? - I told you , I heard something .
- I know you 're trying to scare me .
- I 'm not .
( faint thudding )
What is it ?
I must have left a window in my room open .
( telephone rings )
Could you get that ?
- Marnie ? - Yeah .
( ringing continues )
( beep )
- Hello ? - ( the voice ) Hello . Who is this ?
Marnie . Who 's this ?
This is the last person you 're ever gonna see alive .
- What ? - ( laughs )
( laughing ) I 'm sorry .
I had to .
( sigh ) You bitch .
So not funny .
Somebody falls for it every year .
I don 't see why you get off on this sh ...
( chokes , gasps )
( dial tone ) Marnie ?
( crash )
( beep ) Marnie ?
Marnie ?
Good one , Marnie . Lights out , phone on the floor ?
You know , you really should direct horror films .
Wherever you are .
( sighs ) Let me guess .
You want me to walk by an open doorframe so you can pop out , huh ?
( telephone rings , gasps )
( chuckles ) Okay , timing , timing is perfect .
But you don 't have the app on your phone ,
so you can 't talk like Ghostface , can you ?
( the voice ) Yes I can .
- Who is this ? - Not an app .
Is this Trevor ?
Do I sound like a Trevor to you ? Think of me as your director .
You 're in my movie . You got a fun part , so don 't blow it .
- What movie ? - Same one Marnie 's in .
Only her part got cut way back .
But you , you 're the dumb blonde with the big tits .
We 'll have some fun with you before you die .
I have a 4.0 GPA and 135 IQ , asshole . What did you do with Marnie ?
- She 's on the cutting room floor . - That 's not funny .
This isn 't a comedy . It 's a horror film .
People live , people die . And you 'd better start running .
( crash ) ( screams )
( dog barking in distance )
Marnie ?
( whimpers )
( screams )
( screaming )
( screams again )
( panting )
( breathing heavily )
( screams )
( knife slash ) ( scream )
( grunts )
( garage door whirs )
( door whirs )
( grunting and whimpering )
( screams , crunch )
( whimpering )
( screams )
( woman screams , " Something To Die For " plays )
♪ Working for another hour tonight
♪ Staring at the wall and let the time just pass me by
♪ You might think you know me , but it 's all just a face
♪ Trying to ignore when people screaming my name
♪ When something 's right
♪ Then something is worth to die for
♪ When I feel that something is wrong
♪ Then something is worth to fight for
♪ Don 't say goodbye
♪ Just leave an open door
♪ I wanna hear you say
♪ You give me something to die for ...
What do you think ?
Well , I guess today is the anniversary .
- ( Rebecca sighs ) Kids . - No , I meant the display .
Oh . ( chuckles )
- It 's good . - Told the owner I 'd kill his cat if he didn 't get it right .
( chuckles ) Nice .
( vibrating cell phone playing " Axel F " )
( music stops ) ( vibration begins / ends )
Mmm .
Mm .
( car alarm chirps )
( car approaching , " Cup of Coffee " by The Novocaines blaring )
Ho ! Whoa , whoa , whoa ! 25 , stay alive !
Shit . Sorry , Sheriff !
Kirby .
( " Cup of Coffee " by The Novocaines continues )
Whoo .
( horn honks )
Hey , before you get in the car , you have to promise not to kill me .
Why ? What did you do ?
- Trevor called me last night . - Why is he calling you ?
Because you won 't take his calls .
He knows I have your ear , and he wants to know .
- Know what ? - How upset you are .
Can we just not talk about this now , please ?
( softly ) Fine . Fine .
Okay , so Trevor called me last night .
He called you , too ?
He 's worried your cousin coming to Woodsboro 's
distracting you from knowing how sorry he really is .
- Well , that 's inventive . - ( chuckling ) Oh , God .
( engine starts )
Oh , by the way , have you seen the Grim Reaper , Angel of Death ?
- What are you talking about ? - Your cousin .
Last stop on her book tour ,
first stop on her road to a new life . It 's very dramatic .
She 's the reason why I love horror movies .
I 'm sure she 'd love to hear that . If I knew her , which I don 't really .
Well , wherever she went , people died . Other people ... it was never her .
I mean , " Stab " is the wrong franchise for her .
It should be " Final Destination . " ( cell phone rings )
Okay , why is Jenny Randall calling me ?
I Can not stand Jenny .
- Hello . - ( the voice ) Hello , Jill .
- Why ? - Shh ! Jenny ? Is this you ?
- What 's your favorite scary movie ? - Okay , who is this ?
What does she want ?
( beep ) I said , who is this ?
( angrily ) I asked you a question . What 's your favorite scary movie ?
I 'm hanging up . ( beep )
Wow . ( chuckles ) That was original .
I got a call like that this morning from Marnie the Carny .
- What ? - Watch out ! ( horn blares , tires squeal )
( man ) Nice move , asshole !
( panting ) You just ran a stop sign .
Sorry .
- ( sighs ) - Angel of Death .
( Deputy Judy ) Mayor wants these down before lunch .
( Joe ) Only twenty-five more to go .
- Morning , Sheriff . - Morning , Deputy .
- Joe . - Morning , Sheriff .
Looks like the celebration 's begun .
- High school kids , probably . - Yeah .
One generation 's tragedy is the next one 's joke .
Sorry you can never get away from this .
You know , I wish I 'd been old enough to be part of the force
when you were solving those crimes .
Mmm .
It 's those intense investigations that really bond relationships .
Mmha , yeah .
How is Gale , by the way ?
Gale 's good . She 's writing .
Fiction .
Hey , I made some lemon squares . They 're in my car .
Come on ... thanks , Deputy , but no thanks .
Sheriff , you 're not cheatin ' on your wife if you eat my lemon square .
Yeah , but I would be cheatin ' on my diet . ( both laugh )
( man on radio ) : Sheriff Riley ? Come in , Sheriff Riley !
This is Sheriff Riley . Go ahead . ( click )
You gotta get over to the Randall house right away .
It 's bad , Sheriff , real bad . ( click )
( siren wails , engine starts ) ( tire sqeals )
( second siren begins )
( television ) : The book is " Out of Darkness , "
and its author , Sidney Prescott , is here with us today .
Have the seven " Stab " movies ,
all based on Gale Weathers ' books about you ,
made it even harder to go on ?
I don 't blame Gale . That 's in the past .
If I was a victim for too long , it was up to me to reinvent myself .
- That 's why I wrote this book . - Sidney Prescott , everybody .
And rave reviews for her book " Out of Darkness . "
All right , Gale , let 's do it .
Let 's reinvent myself .
( sighs )
Except ...
I have ...
no fucking idea ...
what to ...
write .
( sighs )
Oh , is that new ?
That 's the 2.0 upgraded version . I 'm totally mobile now .
Nice . Look .
Oh , this is " Hall Pass " with Robbie Mercer ,
here with the luscious Olivia
" Don 't look at my tits , I have a mind " Morris .
Here is my Woodsboro Massacre anniversary question :
What is your favorite scary movie ?
Is that all you 've got ? Some stupid douche question ?
Yeah , where 'd you hear that anyways ?
It 's a line from " Stab One , " duh !
Hey , Charlie .
You 're a - - a genre nut , Kirby . What 's your favorite scary movie ?
- " Bambi . " - Mm mmh .
Dork ! - What ?
That 's funny , Kirby .
( girls chuckle )
Completely unaware you exist .
No , man , she wants me .
Yeah , I wish , right , Asshole ?
I think Charlie likes you .
And I like him .
To tease , to torment , to make him squirm .
You could do a lot worse , trust me .
( gasps )
Oh ! Hi , Trevor . Bye , Trevor .
Can we talk ?
Somebody cares about you over here , you know ?
Someone who made you really happy once .
Someone who never should have let you go .
When you 're done with a phone call , you let someone go .
Or , when you take someone to the airport , you let them go .
When you tell someone you love her and she gives you everything ,
and then you just go out with someone else ,
that is not letting her go , that 's dumping her .
Okay , that 's - - that 's betrayal . ( sighs )
Trevor Sheldon , denied live on " Hall Pass " with Robbie Mercer .
What is your favorite scary movie , man ?
I 'll show you . ( snarls )
( Sidney ) : And I began to believe myself , that was all I was ,
a - - a victim , and that was unacceptable to me .
So , I sat down ...
and began to write a new role that would be my own ,
a role for a woman who could leave the walls of fear behind
and step out into the sunlight , out of darkness .
( applause ) Thank you .
( Rebecca ) : Okay , we 're gonna start the book signing in a sec .
So buy your copies while they last . Lookin ' at you , ladies .
New York Times bestseller . Rave reviews .
Gale . I 'm glad you came .
Congratulations , Sidney .
I haven 't had a chance to read it yet , but - -
I know where you can get one . ( chuckles )
Dewey ! Hey !
Hey , Sidney . Gale , you made it .
( sirens wailing , tires screeching ) What 's going on , Dewey ?
Oh , Sid , I 'm sorry , I gotta do something here .
- Shit ! - I 'm really sorry .
Excuse me ! This will only take a minute .
I need you all to stay where you are and remain silent .
Nobody leaves yet . The Sheriff thanks you .
Can this wait , Barney Fife ? I 'm running an event here .
Ma 'am , this is a police event now .
What 's going on ?
Gale , this is police business . If you could just let us handle this .
I 'm talking to my husband , Deputy Judy .
Listen , there 's a phone we believe
may have been taken from the scene of a crime .
Deputy Hicks has traced its location back to these coordinates .
The rest is need-to-know .
- And I 'm not " need-to-know " ? - Shh .
( cell phone ringing )
Sheriff , it 's ringing out here !
( ringing continues )
There !
- It 's coming from the trunk . - There .
Dewey ! Gonna need everyone to stay back .
- Not now , Sid . - It 's my rental .
( ringing continues )
( everyone gasps )
- Damn ! - Okay , it 's now an official crime scene .
Let 's lock it down . Get that camera outta here ! - It 's a crime scene .
- Everybody back . - Gimme that camera .
Please tell me this is a prank , Dewey .
- I 'm afraid not , Sid . - On the curb , ma 'am .
- Come on . - Everybody , get back ! - Step back ! ( cell phone dialing )
Henry , you 're not gonna believe what just happened .
Stand back , Gale . Gale .
I just wanna see .
( man ) Cover up your kid 's eyes !
Okay , essays are due Tuesday .
" Why Woodsboro is the best - - " ( multiple cell phones ringing )
Anything with an on / off switch should be off , that 's the rule !
Somebody wanna share ?
Jenny Randall and Marnie Cooper were murdered last night .
- What ? ( chattering )
What ?
Stabbed to death .
- What 's your favorite scary movie - - - Shut up ! - Shut up ! - Shut up !
- Yo , it 's a news van ! - Class is not over !
That was fast .
( woman reporter ) This week marks the anniversary of the infamous Woodsboro Murders .
Two girls killed the exact day local celebrity victim Sidney Prescott
chose to return to her hometown .
It all could be something right out of a Gale Weathers ' best-seller .
And where is she now ?
Well , living right here in Woodsboro as the wife of Sherrif Dewey Riley - -
- Mrs. Riley . - Hoss .
- First Lady . - Perkins .
Excuse me , Gale , he 's conducting an interview .
Great . I love interviews .
You 'll have to wait , Gale . Sorry , can 't let you in there .
( chuckles ) What are you gonna do , arrest me , Deputy Judy ?
If it comes to it . Civilian interference with a police investigation
poses many a problem in a court of law .
Okay , listen to me , Judy .
I don 't mind that you 're working with my husband
or that you even bake him those little treats , as you do ,
but , if you 're gonna start acting like him ,
you gotta put a moustache on , ' cause you sound ridiculous .
- Gale ! - Judy ! - Gale ! ( clears throat )
Deputy . Gale .
( whispering ) Please .
Uh , Sidney , if you don 't mind givin ' us a minute .
- Sid . - Hi , Gale .
Dewey , would you please explain to Betty Crocker
that I have every right to be here ?
If there 's been another murder in Woodsboro , obviously ... what ?
( whispering ) That is not public information !
- It is all over the Internet , Dewey ! - It is ?
Yes ! The whole world knows about it before me !
She wants to be a part of the investigation , Sheriff .
( sighs ) Hang on .
Um , are you familiar with the phrase , " I wrote the book on this " ?
Gale , with all due respect , I don 't see how that pertains to - -
Because I wrote the book on this !
" The Woodsboro Murders " by Gale Weathers ?
But you 're not a reporter anymore , Gale .
- Whoa , whoa , whoa , whoa . - And even if you were ...
Don 't treat me like I 'm the media .
I helped solve these things three times , remember ?
You and me . Together .
( sighs ) But I 'm the Sheriff now , Gale .
Right ?
What , you 're not gonna let me help you with this ?
I can 't .
All right , then I 'm going rogue .
This is what I 'm good at , Dewey .
This is what I know how to do .
( clears throat )
Your lemon squares taste like ass .
They don 't . They really don 't .
- Thank you , sir . - Sheriff . - Yeah ?
We 've got a couple high school kids in here .
Two of ' em , they say they got threatening phone calls this morning
from the victims ' phones .
Names are Olivia Morris and Jill Roberts .
That 's Sid 's cousin . Damn .
Right in here , Sheriff .
- Hey , Jill . - Sidney .
- Hi . - Hi .
It 's nice to see you even under the circumstances .
( both chuckle ) You okay ?
- Yeah . - So two of you got phone calls ?
Yeah , us two . " What 's your favorite scary movie ? "
It was the killer 's voice . From " Stab . "
Or , I mean , you know , from your life .
I 'm Kirby , by the way . I 'm their friend .
And the killer didn 't call you ?
No . Is - - is that a bad thing ?
Does that mean that I 'm not gonna live as long as these two ?
( chuckling ) No .
No . Maybe .
Of course not . Just , uh , just be careful .
Oh , my God , did you hear that ? I 'm gonna be next !
Dewey , I shouldn 't be here . I should leave town .
I 'm afraid that 's not really possible , Sidney .
Look , nobody thinks you 're involved , but everyone 's a suspect , I 'm sorry .
And there was evidence in your car , connecting the killer to you .
You may be a material witness . - ( sighs )
So , look , you 'll have , uh , 24-hour police surveillance .
That 's comforting .
( beep ) This is Rebecca .
Oh , my fucking God , Henry ! Yes ! It 's true .
Two girls butchered . ( chuckles ) Payday .
I was so not feeling Woodsboro . I was like , lame PR move , right ?
Well , fuck me wow . Best idea ever .
Henry , I 'll call you back . ( beep )
Excuse me I have to geek out .
I didn 't get a chance to say something earlier ,
but it 's such an honor to meet you .
- Thank you . - Rebecca Walters . - Hi .
When I was a kid , it was all about " Top Story with Gale Weathers . "
- ( chuckles ) You were my ' 90s . - Well , it 's Gale Riley now .
You gave it all up for love , I know that .
How long have you and Dewey been married ?
- Ten years . - Aww !
Just like your characters in " Stab 3 . " Wow .
Wow .
Oh , I didn 't mean bad wow .
It just , it always seemed like more of a movie romance than a real one
because it was a movie and in real life you two would never be - -
Ooh , dug a hole . ( chuckles nervously ) Climbing out , here .
So anyway kudos on being brave enough to drop off the professional map .
Any plans on revitalizing your tarnished brand ?
Listen , in about two seconds , I 'm gonna revitalize your face
with my tarnished brand . - Ooh !
I still got it .
Oh , testy !
( indistinct talking )
She 's so pretty .
I mean when you think about what she survived , she must have scars everywhere .
- ( both ) Shh ! - Come on !
Her mom was my sister . I have scars , too .
No one ever asks me about my scars .
- I 'm sorry , Mrs. Roberts . - She means knife scars , Mom .
Oh .
Well ... fine .
How are you ?
How 's Gale ?
Uh , I 'm all right .
But Gale , uh , it 's been hard on her .
Small town ... small-town husband .
( chuckles humorlessly ) Not much to write about .
You two okay ?
Well , I read somewhere once ,
" Just when you think things can 't get any worse ,
" sometimes they don 't .
( chuckling ) Sometimes they get better . "
" Out of Darkness " by Sidney Prescott , page 220 .
( both chuckle )
Gotta get going .
It 's nice to see you , Dewey . Been through a lot together .
And we 'll get through this , too . Okay ?
- Lock up . - Mm-hmm .
( indistinct police radio chatter )
( dog barking )
- ( gasps ) - Be cool . It 's okay . Relax , relax . It 's just me .
What the hell are you doing here ? There are cops right out front .
No match for the ninja , baby .
( sighs )
Anyway , what are you doing in the house with Sidney Prescott ?
I mean , that 's like being on " Top Chef " with Jeffrey Dahmer .
Can you please get away from the window ?
Y - - you have no right to be in here . Not anymore .
Hang on .
I heard you got a phone call from the killer .
- Is that true ? - ( sighs ) What do you care ?
Don 't you think you 'd be a lot safer with me around ?
- I don 't trust you Trevor . - Hey .
Then I 'm just gonna have to make sure that you do , all right ?
( knock on door )
Oh , sorry , I didn 't - -
No , he 's just leaving . It 's - - it 's my ex .
Oh .
Yeah . Her one and only .
- Hi . - Hi .
It 's cool to meet you ... officially .
I keep meaning to pick up a copy of your book , but - -
- You 're smaller in person . - ( snorts )
( sighs )
( chuckles softly )
What ?
Nothing . You just , uh ... you remind me of , uh
me .
( chuckles softly )
Lock your window , okay ?
Yeah . Good night .
' Night .
- ( gasps ) - Sorry about that .
( Deputy Judy ) Just makin ' my rounds before takin ' off .
Great . Thanks .
Y - - You don 't remember me , do ya ?
Sorry ?
We went to high school together . Judy Hicks ?
We had the same homeroom and Drama Club , too .
We were in " Peter Pan " together .
I played a Lost Boy .
You were ... Tiger Lily .
I 'm sorry , that was a long time ago .
It 's okay , I mean ,
you had ... a lot of stuff ... goin ' on back then .
Well , it 's nice to see you again , Judy .
You too . ( door opens , indistinct radio chatter )
( clears throat ) ( clears throat )
( man ) Everything okay upstairs ?
You 're supposed to be out front , Perkins .
( pop music playing on car radio )
What 's a 4-letter word for " courage " ?
Uh ...
" guts . "
That 's Olivia Morris . She lives next door .
She 's on the list . - Yeah .
She can live next door to me .
( television ) : Now , seriously , uh ... uh , Mary ,
I 'm warning you , okay , I 'm gonna have to get physical .
I mean it . This is it ! - ( snarling )
Just fuck off !
( growling )
( girls laugh )
( cell phone rings )
- Hello ? - What are you guys up to ?
Oh , we 're watching " Shaun of the Dead . "
You know there are two zombies sitting outside the house in a car ?
Yup . They 're cops . You wanna come up ?
The Angel of Death leave ?
No , she 's in the guest room . ( chuckles )
Forget it . Next door 's close enough .
- Your mom home ? - She 's at her boyfriend 's .
It 's creepy around here tonight .
- ( laughs ) - Well , the zombies are still in their car .
So you should be all right .
- Call me tomorrow , okay ? - All right .
- She didn 't wanna come up ? - She fears the Reaper .
Watch this .
( television silenced )
( cell phone rings )
Speaking .
( imitating Ghostface ) What 's your favorite scary movie , Olivia ?
That 's the worst imitation I 've ever heard , Jill .
Speaking of " Stab , " you heard where the Stab-a-Thon 's gonna be yet ?
( beep ) No , and it doesn 't matter to me anyways .
My mom doesn 't want me to go .
( cell phone rings ) ( sighs ) It 's Trevor .
- I 'll handle this . - Trevor 's calling . Again .
- What do you want ? - ( the voice ) I wanna talk to Jill .
Uh , no , it 's Kirby . Sorry , Trevor .
Jill is screening her calls from all past relationships .
What 's going on over there ?
Hang on a sec . What is he saying ?
( whispers ) I 'm not Trevor .
W - - what ? I can barely hear you , Trevor .
This isn 't Trevor .
Oh , a - - all right .
Well , then , why do you have his phone , whoever this is ?
( whispering ) He 's trying to do Ghostface . ( laughs )
( chuckles ) He 's being weird .
I wanna talk to Jill .
Okay , well , she doesn 't wanna talk to you .
Come on , Mr. Ghostface , whisper to me .
Aren 't you supposed to ask me a question ?
All right . How 's the movie ?
What movie ?
" Shaun of the Dead . "
How did you know that ?
Because I 'm standing in the closet .
Stop . You are not .
- What 's going on ? - Trevor 's being weird .
- I mean , if it is him , I don 't know . - What ?
This is not fucking Trevor !
Well then , who the fuck are you ?
Open the closet door .
You do know there are cops all over this house ?
I think I 'd have just enough time to slice someone open .
- I - - I 'll talk to him . - Shh !
What 's going on over there , you guys ?
S - - Sorry . I - - I don 't know , Kirby .
- Shh . - Kirby .
Come on , do it .
There is no way you 're in there .
See for yourself .
Kirby ?
Kirby , come on . Talk to me . This isn 't funny .
Kirby !
( gasps )
Liar . I 'm over this .
I never said I was in your closet .
Wha - -
( crash ) ( Olivia screams )
Oh , my God . Olivia !
( Olivia screaming ) - Oh , my God , help ! - Help !
Aaagh ! ( gasping )
( crash )
No !
( Olivia screams )
( crying ) - No ! - No !
Help !
( slashing ) ( grunting and panting )
Help ! Help !
( slash )
- Hoss ! - Somebody help !
- Perkins ! - ( Olivia screams )
Shit !
Help ! Help !
( girls screaming )
( both screaming )
( breaking glass )
( multiple screams and cries )
( panting )
( door creaks )
( gasps )
( cell phone rings )
- What ? - ( the voice ) Welcome home , Sidney . Preview of coming events .
Why don 't you come for me ? You got the balls for that ?
Oh , poor Sidney . You think this is all about you .
- You think you 're still the star . - This isn 't a fucking movie !
- It will be . - These are innocent people .
( angrily ) Spare me the lecture .
You 've done very well by all this bloodshed , haven 't you ?
Well , how about the town you left behind ?
I 've got plans for you .
I 'm gonna slit your eyelids in half so you don 't blink
when I stab you in the face .
You 'll die when I want you to , Sidney . Not a moment before .
Until then ... you 're going to suffer .
( click )
- Sidney ? - Jill !
- Stay right there ! - Is she - -
Do not look . Okay ?
She said you were the Angel of Death .
- Look out ! - ( screams )
( grunting and panting )
( glass breaking )
( struggling )
( kick )
Have a look . Look over there !
He 's in here !
Where is he ?
He was . - ( police radio ) : What is your status ?
- Jill ? - ( breathes heavily ) Don 't .
( wimpering )
- What happened ? - ( Jill whimpering )
Oh , my God , Jill .
Jesus ! .. I 'll hold you up ! Hey , come on , let 's go . Let 's go .
I 'll take care of you , all right ? I got it .
Jill ?
Oh , my God . Are you okay ?
- Here , keep pressure on it . - There 's nobody back there .
- I 'll call it in . - Right .
Hey . Are you okay ?
You should look upstairs .
( indistinct conversations )
( woman ) Let 's get the coroner 's van brought around , please .
( indistinct radio chatter )
( woman 2 ) You 've got to move over !
( woman 3 ) It 's all your fault , Sidney !
( woman 4 ) Just like your mother !
( man ) What 's going on ? - ( man 2 ) Come on !
I 'm sorry about what I said .
Do you wanna go get that looked at ?
Yeah .
What the hell happened ?
Okay . I saw him go into that yard two houses down right before - -
Yeah , and I circled around to cut him off .
And ?
And I met Hoss coming from the other direction .
No , no , he must 've circled back around somehow . He 's like a ghost .
- Chief , we 're sorry . - We feel terrible .
( sighs ) All right . Get outta here .
( siren wails )
( exhales loudly )
This is " Hall Pass " with Robbie Mercer ,
webcasting live in our darkest hour .
What began as a day of remembrance has ended with serial murder .
Olivia Morris , who officially will never go out with me , is dead .
So is Jenny Randall and Marnie Cooper .
Our local legacy , the " Stab " movies , is coming to life .
Excuse me . Are you recording with that thing ?
Live video-blog upload . He 's webcasting right now .
Oh ! Mind turning it off for a little old-school off the record ?
Can 't . Owe it to my audience .
Turn that fucking thing off .
Okay .
So , you two are the boys that run
the movie club at Woodsboro High , huh ?
Well , Charlie runs it . I 'm just V.P. In case he takes a bullet
It 's called Cinema Club .
So you must have a very unique insight into the movie buffs at your school .
Maybe .
What if we could catch the killer by working together ?
Two generations of cutting-edge journalists
intertwining our passions for media ?
What would you say ?
I love you .
Hmm , very good .
Now you give me your expertise on the gore geek scene at Woodsboro High
and maybe I give you something in return .
Say , a celebrity visit to your Cinema Club ? ( laughs )
By me .
What about Sidney ?
- What about Sidney ? - Yeah , you know her , right ? - I mean , you 're friends with her ?
No offense , but that 'd be a big deal for Cinema Club .
A visit from Sidney Prescott ? I mean , she 's the star .
( chuckles bitterly ) Yes , she 's
Daniel Radcliffe to my J.K. Rowling .
Well ... without the book sales and the box office .
Whatever .
There 's no broken bones .
I think you 'll be fine . Now we just ... take a couple of weeks off .
( indistinct hospital p.a. )
So , Sidney , ooh , ow . ( chuckles )
Anyway , long story short ,
Random wants to lock you in to three more books ... now !
See the blank line in your contract ? You can name your price .
And as soon as you 're clear in this investigation ,
we 're on the next plane to New York .
I booked " Today , " " The View , " " Nancy Grace , " " MTV News " - -
Excuse me . Can I ask you a question ?
- Mm ? - Did you read my book ?
Thought I 'd wait for the movie . ( nervous laugh )
Book tour 's over .
Sidney .
Accept your situation .
You 're a victim . For life .
So embrace it , use it .
I know you care about your readers .
All those little downtrodden fucks that just need a light
at the end of their tunnel so they don 't jump off a bridge .
And a lucky break like this ?
I 'm talkin ' 100 % increase in sales , minimum .
That 's maybe a million more people get your message ,
and you get a ton more checks .
Win-win .
( exhales ) I won 't be needing you anymore .
- Sidney . - You 're fired
- Fired ? - Fired .
Fine .
( running footsteps ) ( door opens )
( elevator bell )
" Have you even read my book , Rebecca ? "
( odd mechanical sounds )
( sighs softly )
The problem with Sidney is that she never gets laid .
Or even a little shit-faced once in a while .
She 'll call me tonight and apologize .
( elevator bell ) Just watch .
She 'll come around .
Gotta just give her time , and Sidney will come ' a-round . '
Where did I ?
( car alarm chirps ) ( chirps again )
Ah . ( cell phone rings )
This is Rebecca .
( the voice ) Sidney Prescott , please .
I 'm handling Miss Prescott 's calls and appearances . May I take a message ?
You are the message .
Are you writing this down ?
Yes , I am .
It 's kind of hard to hear you . I 'm in the hospital with Sidney .
If you could just hang on one second .
( chuckles ) I 've got time .
It 's you that doesn 't .
( car alarm blares )
You know , Rebecca , it doesn 't sound to me like you 're in the hospital . ( she gasps )
Sounds like you 're in a parking garage .
A dark and deserted parking garage .
But if you want to be in the hospital , I 'd be happy to put you there .
In the morgue !
( cell phone rings ) ( keys drop to floor ) Aagh !
Shit !
( phone continues ringing ) No !
( keys jangle )
( engine tries to turn over )
( tries engine again )
( Rebecca screams )
Help !
Help ! Help me !
( tires squeal ) ( Rebecca screams )
Whoo !
Cut and run , you fucking bastard .
( doors unlocking )
( car alarm blaring ) ( screams )
Huh .
Huh !
( screams )
( silence )
( slash )
( Dewey ) : This is an ongoing investigation .
Rest assured , we 're pursuing a number of leads .
- Sheriff ! - The less I say about that , the better . - Sheriff !
- So I 'm taking questions . - Sheriff ! Sheriff ! - Sheriff . - Sheriff ! - Sheriff ! - Sheriff .
- Dewey ! - Gale ?
Any comment on the fact that these killings
seem to resemble the pattern of the original Woodsboro Murders ?
Hon ? ( feedback ) ( whispers ) Later .
( woman ) What was that , Sheriff ?
As I was saying , uh , my officers are hard at work ,
and we just want the community to know that we are very close
to bringing this whole situation under control - - ( woman screams )
( all scream )
( crash )
Someone , get up to the top of the structure ! Go , go !
- Everyone back ! Stay back ! - All right , nobody move !
Listen , I want a man on each stairwell !
- You see anybody ? - ( radio ) Nobody up here .
There 's nobody up there , Sheriff !
It 's all under control , huh , Sheriff ?
What am I supposed to say ?
Listen , I may not be wearing a uniform ,
but I happen to have a lead , and you don 't .
So let me know when you 're back on ' Team Gale . '
Move it , amateurs !
( chattering )
Okay , Cinema Club . We are now in session .
Welcome . Tell you a little bit about ourselves ,
We are a sanctioned after-school activity ,
one rung below the Glee Club , two above Nintendo Wii Fit . ( sparse laughs )
And ( chuckles ) let me just say to our guest , Sidney Prescott ,
it 's an honor . ( applause )
Beyond Jamie Lee Curtis , forget Linda Blair .
I mean , this is the ultimate .
Thanks . I guess .
Um this , you film your entire high school experience
and , what ? Post it on the net ?
Everybody 'll be doing it someday , Sid .
It 's kind of the one component the killer is missing .
Wait . What do you mean ?
Well , if you wanna be the new , new version ,
the killer should be filming the murders .
It 's like the natural next step in a psycho slasher innovation .
I mean , you film ' em all real-time , and then before you get caught ,
you upload ' em into cyberspace . - Making your art as immortal as you .
- Not to implicate him . - Not to implicate me .
So who do you think is behind the murders ?
( beep ) Well , it 's a " Stab " fanatic clearly .
Working on less of a shriekquel and ... and more of a scream-make .
- Copyrighted terms , by the way . - ' Cause all there are now are remakes .
Only horror the studios green-light . I mean ,
- Psst . - There are still rules .
But the rules have changed . The unexpected is the new clichй .
Yeah , you gotta have an opening sequence that blows the doors off ,
dial up some flashy music-video direction ,
and the kills gotta be way more extreme .
Modern audiences get savvy to the rules of the originals .
So the reversals become the new standard .
In fact , the only surefire way to survive a modern horror movie ?
You pretty much have to be gay . ( light chuckling )
So why are you so sure that the killer 's working by the rules of a horror remake ?
Well , the original " Stab " structure is pretty apparent .
Yeah , two kids killed in a house when their parents are away ?
And then the school 's hot chick savaged beyond recognition .
- We all know where it goes from there . - A party .
Exactly . A party .
Guaranteed third-act main cast bloodbath .
Fingers crossed on some nudity for a change .
( light laughter )
Okay , so do you know of a party that 's happening tonight ?
Well , there 's Stab-a-Thon .
Stab-a-Thon ?
Uh , it 's a movie marathon . All seven " Stabs " back-to-back .
- We do it every year . - And it 's tonight ?
( scoffs ) There 's a killer out there patterning his murders after the original movie .
I know . It 's pretty wild .
- Well , you have to call it off . - Um , okay , I mean , it 's Friday .
I 'm sure we 're not the only party that 's goin ' on in Woodsboro .
Where is this circle jerk gonna take place ?
- So who 's ready for this Q and A ? - No , no . I really want the location .
You know , it 's kind of an underground thing .
E-mail invites , pretty secret .
( chuckles ) What , you 're not gonna tell me ?
Really ?
We 're working together . Remember ?
( swallows ) So you ready for that Q and A ?
- Fuck you . - Let 's go .
( chuckles softly ) That was awesome .
- No one brings the girls , unless we say so . - Got it !
( sighs ) I feel like I 'm under house arrest .
You know when people say , " I know how you feel , "
but you know they 're just saying that because they really have
no frigging idea how you feel ?
I know how you feel .
I ... am so sorry about Olivia .
I 'm sorry about your publicist .
How do you handle it ? People staring at you all the time ?
People stare at me ?
( both chuckle )
I could never handle that kind of attention .
I just ... feel like it would take over your whole life .
Ah - -
What I do is I ...
try not to think about me .
I have people I care about . I focus on them .
And the rest , it , um , it works out .
You saved my life last night .
I mean , I know we 're family , but you hardly know me .
Makes me wonder , you know , if
... I 'd have been brave enough to do the same thing .
I really hope you never have to find that out .
Well , if you need me , you know where to find me .
I 'll be up in my cell , or , I mean , my room .
Her room 's all boarded up . That 's the view from my cell .
( sighs ) It 's really weird .
( Kirby ) I think Olivia would understand , okay ?
She 'd want me to be around other people .
Holy shit . ( door shuts )
Even if I did just crash-land on ' Planet Dork ' - -
Speaking of which , Trevor 's here . - Hey , Kirby .
What is he doing there ? That is so not his scene .
I have no idea . Maybe he thought you would be here .
Yeah , fat chance . After what happened last night ?
I mean , my mom is just completely freaked out . It 's not pretty .
All right , look , you go do your " good girl " thing , and I will drink for the both of us .
I will keep you posted .
All right . Be safe .
( rock music playing , indistinct conversations )
( crowd chanting in unison ) Stab-a-thon ! Stab-a-thon ! Stab-a-thon !
( applause and cheers )
Thank you !
( crowd cheering - - indistiguishable )
Mmm .
Cinema Club thanks you for coming out for our third annual Stab-a-thon .
( cheers and applause ) Safety in numbers , my friends ! Safety within the walls .
Who 's ready to drink every time someone can 't get a cell phone signal ? ( cheers and applause )
Who 's ready to drink every time someone shuts the refrigerator door ,
and oh , my God , there 's a harmless character right behind it ? ( hooting and cheering )
Who 's ready to drink every time someone screams the word ...
( all ) No !
So let 's get this Stab-a-thon started ! ( audience applause and cheers )
( eerie music plays )
( cheers and applause )
- Hey , watch it ! - Get out of the way !
- Down in front ! - Move your ass !
- Screw you ! ( angry shouting )
( dramatic music playing )
( glass shatters , audience cheering )
( audience hooting )
( from film ) Yes !
( thunder crashes on film , audience cheers )
Oh , yeah ! Back on my game .
( exhales ) Perfect !
New work-in-progress , chapter one . ( exhales )
When I moved to Woodsboro , I never in a million years dreamed
that I would again play the critical role
in solving another series of these - -
What the hell ?
( cell phone rings )
Gale , where are you ?
I followed the kids to the Stab-a-thon .
There 's an old abandoned farm on Fort Dillon Road .
Listen , I 've got it under surveillance , and I - - I
... I think the killer 's about to make his move .
What makes you so sure ?
You do a remake to out-do the original ,
that 's what the kids said .
This party is all about the " Stab " movies .
Come on ! How ' meta ' can you get ?
How " what-a " can you get ?
I don 't know . I heard them say it .
Dewey , listen to me , you have to get out here .
Come on , you catch the killer , I get the story .
It 's a win-win .
( sarcastically ) Well , I thought you were going rogue , Gale .
Oh , co ... are you serious ? Come on !
( sighs ) Forget it ! Thanks for having faith in me !
I gotta fix my equipment . ( beep )
Gale !
Shit !
( siren wails )
( audience man ) Why don 't you get more comfortable , baby ?
( whistles and cat calls )
( cheers )
( tipsy ) Bravo . Well ... very well done ! Very ... I 'm very impressed .
Kind of ... kind of impressed . Not really .
- That 'll do . - Yeah ? - Yeah . - I mean she wants it . - Yeah
( telephone rings )
( audience groans )
( cheers and applause ) Ghostface ! Yeah !
( woman ) Don 't answer it !
- Hello ? - ( Ghostface ) Hello .
Who is this ?
( audience mimicking dialogue ) - Were you expecting somebody ? - Hello ?
( indistinct police radio chatter )
( audience talking along ) You know , I don 't even know you , and I dislike you already .
Hicks , how far are you from Fort Dillon Road ?
- Five minutes at the most , sir . - Well , step on it .
( tense music playing )
( Ghostface ) Look out your window .
( glass breaking ) ( audience screaming )
( camera whirring )
Gale ! Gale , behind you !
( gasps )
( slash )
( screams nearly drowned-out by audience )
Aah !
( grunts )
Gale !
( screaming )
( onscreen woman screams )
( grunts )
Aaah !
Freeze !
( gunshot )
( slash )
Unh !
( screams from audience )
( gunshot )
( all screaming )
Get out of the way , you morons !
( slams )
Damn it !
Okay , put pressure on that .
Did you catch him ?
No . Hopefully your cameras caught something .
- They weren 't the only ones Dewey . - What ?
There 's a webcam that 's hidden up there .
- It was watching me . - A webcam ?
He 's recording the murders .
What ?
This time ... he 's making the movie .
Sidney Prescott detail . Man , I don 't ... like it .
The cops guarding the house , they always get it .
- What are you talkin ' about ? - It 's a movie cop rule .
Sucks to be a cop in a movie , unless you 're Bruce Willis .
Not all cops die in movies .
No , but if it 's your last day before retirement , you do .
If you 're a rookie , just found out your wife is pregnant , you do .
Or if your partner 's better-looking than you , you do , and by the way ...
( both ) I win that one .
( both chuckle )
You know what ? I 'll take the next perimeter .
I 'll be right back .
Shit ! I know this one .
You 're not supposed to say that , are you ?
Eh , new decade , new rules .
You know , these days , you might come back , find me dead ,
eyes gouged out , tongue sticking out .
- Could go either way . - I gotta learn this shit . - Okay ...
( chuckles ) I 'll take this one .
Hey , Hoss ,
Be careful .
I 'm always careful .
Dead man walking .
( cat screeches then yowls )
( wind chimes tinkling )
( wind chimes continue )
( crickets )
Perkins , was there a window open on your last perimeter check ?
Perkins , come in , over .
( dog barking in distance )
( door creaks )
( whispers ) Anthony ?
( whispering ) Perkins ?
- Aaah ! - Ohh !
- ( laughs ) - Damn it .
You should 've seen the look on your face , rookie .
- ( strangled grunt ) - Hoss !
What the fuck ? Aah !
Oh , shit .
Ugh .
Aaah !
Hoss !
Uah .
( grunts )
Aigh ! ( dogs barking in distance )
( dogs barking in distance )
Fuck Bruce Willis .
( wind chimes tinkling )
( floor creaking )
( chimes and creaking )
( chimes dogs barking )
Sorry ! The wind chimes were over here .
That was me . I was trying to fix ' em , sorry .
I 'm just back from the store .
You 're shopping ?
My stress buster . Got one more bag in the car .
I 'll Be right back .
( door creaks )
( dogs barking )
( telephone rings )
( ringing continues )
Jill , you gonna get that ?
( beep ) Roberts ' residence .
( the voice ) You 're a survivor , aren 't you , Sidney ?
Your one and only skill . You survive .
I have one question for you .
What good 's it to be a survivor in this little drama
if everyone close to you is dead ?
- Who are you ? - Turn on the TV to channel 6 .
Who the fuck are you ?
Turn it on . Watch the teaser .
( man on TV ) ... nearly turned deadly tonight with the latest victims of these attacks
being the wife of the Woodsboro sheriff , Gale Riley ;
AKA : Gale Weathers who 's in serious condition tonight after being stabbed .
Her assailant then disappeared in a sea of identic - -
( TV off ) ( laughs ) Glad you came home , Sidney ? Has it been worth it yet ?
- Why are you doing this ? - Ah , friends count .
But it 's the family ties that cut deep , am I right ?
What do you mean ?
( chuckles ) The ones you care about most .
And what 's closer than family ? The bond of blood .
- Don 't . - You can 't save them . All you can do is watch . ( laughs )
Jill !
( panting )
Kate ?
- Sid ? - Jill 's not in her room .
- Oh , my God ! - She 's gone to Kirby 's .
You gotta call her and get her back here . - Okay - -
( beep ) ( ringing )
Come on , Jill .
Leave a message .
She 's not picking up ! What 's going on ?
The killer called . He 's coming after me ,
but he wants my family first .
- Oh , God , Jill ! - Let 's get the cops .
- The cops aren 't there . - What ?
They were there when I first came in , but they 're not there now .
Let 's get to Kirby 's .
Out the front .
( both gasp )
Aaah !
Brace it from the bottom . Can you ?
( straining )
( grunts )
( knob jiggling ) Let 's get outta here .
- ( thud , grunts ) - ( whispering ) Kate , come on !
Tell Jill ... I 'm so ... sorry .
Shh !
( begins gasping )
Kate ?
Hicks ? What are you doing ?
I just saw somebody coming around the side of the house .
Where are Hoss and Perkins ? I couldn 't get them on the radio .
Whose blood is that ?
It 's - - it 's Kate 's . We were just attacked .
- She 's dead . - Where is she ?
- Front door . - Show me .
Okay .
- Stay here . - Okay .
( radio clicks ) This is Deputy Hicks .
I 've got a homicide at the Roberts residence .
No sign of Perkins or Hoss .
( radio ) Copy that , we 'll try to locate them .
I 'm so sorry - -
( tires squealing )
You 're gonna be fine . All right ? I swear !
No more " on your own . "
It 's you and me , forever .
One , two , three . ( grunts )
Easy !
- Dewey ? - Yeah ?
Promise me something .
Anything .
( exhales ) Catch that motherfucker .
- Absolutely . I love you . - I love you .
You missed chaos . Utter chaos .
- I can 't believe that . - The sheriff 's wife , man !
She told us to cancel it , and we didn 't , and now this ?
- What are we supposed to do ? - Robbie , calm down .
It makes sense . This is what the re-boots do .
They - - they one-up the original ending .
The Woodsboro murders ended at a party . So in the remake - -
The party 's the false ending . New rules .
Exactly .
Okay , no offense , guys , but I 'm gonna put in " Stab 7 . " - ( Kirby ) Yes !
- Nobody cancels my film festival . - Whoa , whoa , whoa .
I don 't wanna watch that , not after what happened to Olivia .
Oh , come on , it was her favorite .
Oh , wow , Kirby . You got some classics here .
- Yup . - " Suspiria , " " Don 't Look Now . "
You know it . I could trivia your ass under the table , ' Cinema Boy . '
Oh , yeah ? Who played Leatherface first ?
- Gunnar Hansen . - Wow . Did you feel that ?
That charge that moved between us just then ?
Oh , that was me . I have powers .
So sexy .
You guys are unbelievable . You 're playing fuckin ' trivia games ?
The cops are gonna come for us . They 're gonna shut down my website .
- We 're so dead ! - Yeah . I agree .
- Jesus Christ , where 'd you come from ? - The front door .
By the way , Kirby , with everything that 's going on right now ,
you probably shouldn 't leave that unlocked .
Sorry .
And , um , may I ask , what the hell you 're doing here ?
What ? Didn 't I find the after-party ?
No , you found the anti-party , and it 's invitation only .
Yeah , well , I got an invitation . From Jill .
- So , what 's the story ? - Eh , ah , w - - what ?
You sent me a text message . " After-party at Kirby 's house .
- I mean , it was from your phone . - What do you mean from my phone ?
W - - where is my phone ? I think I left it in your car .
I didn 't text him . ( sighs ) I didn 't text you .
And I 'll prove it .
So , Charlie , Robbie ,
how 's it feel to be accessories to a crime , huh ?
I mean , really , Dewey 's wife ?
My life is over .
So which one of you guys sent me a text message from Jill 's phone , huh ?
( snorts , coughs )
We 're supposed to accept that you 're telling the truth ?
Isn 't your phone missing ?
- Got a new one . - Really .
Oh , that 's incredibly convenient .
- Dewey , it 's Hicks . - What 's up ?
- Kate Roberts is dead . - Huh ?
And Sidney fled the scene .
What ? What happened to Kate ?
She was stabbed just like the others .
- What about Jill ? - No sign of her at all .
Where the hell were Hoss and Perkins ?
They were found dead in their car two blocks away .
( sighs ) Multiple stab wounds
Okay . ( sighs )
I 'm on my way .
Yes , sir .
( tires screeching )
( siren wails )
( on screen ) Wrong number . ( beep )
- Who was that ? - Oh , nobody .
- Did you pick a movie ? - Yeah . We 're gonna go scary .
- " Saw 4 . " - Ugh , I saw that in theaters .
It sucks . It 's not scary , it 's gross , I mean , you know - -
( groans )
( slash ) Well , I like Jigsaw . I think he kills people very creatively - -
( owl hoots )
( owl hoots again )
( groans )
Charlie , you want to sit over here next to me ?
( sighs )
All right .
Get ready for a " Hall Pass " with Robbie Mercer extra .
Now tonight , there is a good chance that Charlie Walker ,
yes , my Charlie Walker , may get lucky with a girl .
Now I 'm unable to , uh , divulge my exact location , however ,
suffice it to say , Woodsboro High may be in store for some geek history .
We 'll see .
( clears throat )
( distant thud )
( owl hoots )
( owl hoots again )
Hello ?
Who 's there ?
Oh , my God - -
( plant squeaks as it swings )
( owl hoots )
( owl hoots again )
( film ) - Where are you going ? - To make sure the front door is locked .
( doorbell rings , both scream )
No , don 't . Don 't open it - -
- ( whispering ) Hey , Charlie ? - Yeah ?
I 'm sorry , I know you 're into the movie and all ,
but now would be a really good time to make a move .
For ... me to make a move ?
Ummm .
Couldn 't you make a move ?
I just did .
' Cause you 're actually pretty cute .
Especially when I 'm scared and ... lonely ... and drunk .
Hey , guys , did - - did you see Jill ... come in ?
I didn 't see her outside .
Yes , Trevor , she is upstairs .
Thank God you 're here to protect her when you can 't even find her .
( film ) There 's nobody out here .
( chuckles ) Oh , dude , I love this part of the movie .
( sighs )
Yeah , yeah , yeah .
Just when you think they 're all safe and comfortable in the house ...
Ghostface comes in , and , bam !
Did I just interrupt something right here ?
Shut the fuck up . ( chuckles )
Who invited you , Trevor ?
( chuckling ) All right . Clearly not you .
Wow . I 'm gonna be upstairs . ( exhales sharply )
Get out of my house !
Yeah , yeah .
Okay , I 'm a little drunk , so don 't blame your internet connection . ( chuckles )
Let 's see what Charlie 's up to , shall we ?
Or the saga of Trevor and Jill .
Oh , the intrigue of Woodsboro High .
Who needs a killer around when there 's so much drama ?
( chuckles ) Oh , man .
Yeah .
That 's better . ( door opens , creaking )
( gasps ) Aah !
Oh !
( slash ) Aah ! Aah-ha-ho !
Wait , no , you can 't ! You can 't ! There 's rules !
I - - I 'm gay ! I 'm gay !
I mean , if it helps .
( grunts )
( film ) ... random girl who gets a call
that undoubtedly ends up getting her killed .
It 's all so predictable . There 's no element of surprise .
You can see ev - - ( Turns off )
( odd faint ' sawing ' sound )
( dramatic music )
Kirby !
I found my phone . It was up in your room .
There was no text message sent to Trevor .
He is such a liar . Where is he ?
What do you mean where is he ? He just went upstairs looking for you .
He 's not upstairs .
Trevor ?
Charlie ? Robbie ?
Maybe they 're outside ?
- ( screams ) - Jill .
Sidney , I - - I 'm sorry , I should 've told you and Mom where I was going .
No , it 's okay . It 's just , I-I need you to come with me . Come with me right now , okay ?
( gasps )
Run .
Robbie !
( screaming )
Go !
( all breathing heavily / gasping )
- Sidney ! - ( grunts )
Come on !
- The balcony ! - There 's no other way out ?
We can jump . ( thudding , wood cracking )
It 's two stories . Where 's your cell ?
- Uh , here . - Get under the bed !
- What ? - Just do what I say ! Get under the bed .
Don 't make a sound and don 't come out until I come get you , okay ?
- Just trust me . - Okay .
( crash )
( footsteps )
You got it ? You 're okay ? Jill , run ! Just keep running ! Get help !
( phone dialing )
( telephone line ringing )
( exhales )
( grunts ) ( line ringing continues )
( grunts ) ( panting )
( line ringing ) - ( click ) Hello ? - Dewey !
- Sidney , where are you ? - I 'm at Kirby 's .
The killer is here . I need your help .
- I 'm on my way . - Okay .
( grunts )
Sidney ? Sidney !
I need all units to 329 Whispering Lane .
All units , 329 Whispering Lane !
( gasps )
( slash )
( sirens wailing )
( gasps ) Sorry . It 's just me .
Look , I tried to call 911 , but the landline 's dead
... and someone smashed the router - I think I got through on my cell .
Okay , where 's Jill ? ( footsteps overhead )
We 'll go and hide . Go , go , go , go .
( lock clicks )
There 's a room down here . We can lock ourselves in .
I heard you yelling to Jill . Did she get away ?
I think she 's safe .
( lock clicks )
( thudding ) Kirby , let me in !
Charlie .
No . No , no , no , no .
I just found Robbie . This - - this is his blood .
Please . Please . There is someone else out here .
- Let me in ! - If you can 't trust him , don 't open the door .
My God , let me in !
Get away from the door , Charlie .
Kirby , it is me . Please let me in !
It 's me !
( voice breaking ) I 'm sorry , I can 't .
- What the fuck ? ! - ( whispers ) I 'm sorry .
Behind you ! Look out !
( Charlie grunts ) ( Kirby gasps )
( Charlie ) : ( grunts ) No ! No , no , no !
( Charlie ) : Kirby !
( sirens wailing )
( Kirby ) : ( sighs ) Oh , God , no , please . ( pounds on door )
Leave him alone ! ( panting )
Leave him alone !
( cell phone ringing )
It 's Charlie 's phone . ( electronic click )
( the voice ) Tell Sidney heads are gonna roll tonight .
Tell Sidney it 's all because of her .
Or maybe she wants to take his place .
I promise to be quick .
- It 's him . - Okay , okay . I 'm gonna get Jill .
We should be in the same place . Just - - just keep him on the phone .
I 'll be right back , okay ?
( gasping ) Let him go , please .
I hear you like horror movies , Kirby ,
but do you like ' em as much as him ?
Forget watching " Stab . " You get to live it
No , no , no , no , no ! He 's the expert ! It 's not me !
Warm-up question : Jason 's weapon ?
Uh , it 's a machete .
There , you see ? You do know the genre .
- Michael Myers ? - Uh , butcher knife . Leatherface ?
A chainsaw . Please !
Just ask Sidney if you need some help . Freddy Krueger ?
Uh , uh , razor hands .
Name the movie that started the slasher craze .
" Halloween , " " Texas Chainsaw Massacre , " " Last House on the Left , " or " Psycho " ? ( muffled cries from Charlie )
- " Psycho " ! - None of the above !
" Peeping Tom , " 1960 , directed by Michael Powell .
First movie to ever put the audience in the killer 's POV .
What ? Wait . No , no , no . ( gasping )
Please , just ask me one more question ! Just one more !
All right , Kirby .
Then it 's time for your last-chance question .
Name the remake of the groundbreaking horror movie in which the villain - -
Uh , " Halloween , " uh , " Texas Chainsaw , " " Dawn Of The Dead , "
" The Hills Have Eyes , " " Amityville Horror , "
uh , " Last House On The Left , " " Friday The Thirteenth , "
" A Nightmare On Elm Street , " " My Bloody Valentine , "
" When A Stranger Calls , " " Prom Night , " " Black Christmas , "
" House Of Wax , " " The Fog , " uh , " Piranha . "
It 's one of those , right ? Right ?
( exhales ) I got it right .
I was fucking right .
( whispers ) Jill ?
( gasps ) ( unlocking )
I won , Charlie . I fucking won .
I won . He tried to beat me , but I fucking won .
Great , Kirby .
( Kirby gasping ) I won .
( dogs barking ) Okay . Almost there .
Just hang tight . Okay . Okay .
- All right . - Kirby ?
- Yeah ? - This is making a move . - ( gasps )
( gasps )
Four years of classes together , and you notice me now ?
- ( Kirby gasping ) - Stupid bitch ! It 's too late !
( grunting )
Shh . Shh .
Oh , I know , I know .
- ( Kirby Gasps ) - It 's okay . Take your time
Doesn 't happen as fast as it does in the movies , I know . - ( she gasps )
- Ch - - ( gasps ) Char - - ( gasps ) - Just a second !
( grunting ) ( gurgling of blood )
( door opening and squeaking )
( gasps , breathes heavily ) ( footsteps downstairs )
Kirby ? ( door opening )
( she grunts )
( gasping )
You know , you learn a lot when you watch movies over and over .
All the plots are about trying to kill YOU .
( gasping ) Where 's Jill ?
Oh , you think she 's gonna get away ?
You think anyone gets away ?
( both grunt )
( she grunts then gasps )
- Jill ? - Hello , Sidney .
Surprised ?
Watch this .
This is the part , my dear cousin ,
when the cameras
turn off . - ( Sidney gasps ) ( beep )
( Sidney gasps )
Charlie ?
Already taken care of .
Man , I got great footage of my Robbie kill .
Better than Jenny and Marnie or Olivia even .
Good , we 'll cut and upload it later and make it all traceable to Trevor .
Speaking of which ...
- Remind you of anything ? - Jill , please - -
Shut up ! Dick - -
Everything I learned , I learned from you .
You think you had a shitty boyfriend , Sidney ?
Here 's one that fucks you ,
dumps you ,
and doesn 't even make you famous .
Dagh ! What the fuck , Jill ? I loved you !
Shut the fuck up already !
Agh ! Aagh !
I 'm sure those cops would want you to have this , Jill .
For your protection .
( gasps ) No - -
Nn-nnh !
( sobbing ) Baby , please - -
Shouldn 't have killed all these people , Trev .
Gone and put it on video even .
But it means a lot that you did it for me .
What the fuck are you talking about ?
I am not ... the girl ... you cheat on .
( gunshot ) Aagh ! Aaaagh ! ahah .
( screams ) ( cries )
I 've gone through everything . We 're definitely good on timeline .
Oh , yeah . We 're perfect .
No , no , no , please !
( gunshot ) ( splatter sound )
( exhales )
Ready for act three ?
Got it figured out yet , Sidney ?
In keeping with our remake theme ,
Trevor 's this generation 's Billy Loomis ,
and we 're the innocent victims , Sidney and Randy .
See , with you , the world just heard about what happened .
But with us , they 're gonna see it . ( screaming on video )
It 's gonna be a worldwide sensation .
I mean , people gotta see this shit .
It 's not like anyone reads anymore .
( screaming on video )
We 're gonna know fame
like you never even dreamed of .
Last two teenagers standing .
This time Randy gets the girl .
You were amazing . You 're the perfect victim .
I was so believable today , wasn 't I ?
I mean , I told so many lies that I actually started to believe them .
I really think that I was born for this .
How could you do this ?
Do you know what it was like growing up in this family ?
Related to you ?
I mean , all I ever heard was Sidney this
and Sidney that and Sidney , Sidney , Sidney .
You were always just so fucking special !
Well , now I 'm the special one .
You 'll slip . They always do .
Hm ! Come on , Charlie , let 's get on with this .
You have to be strong
and hold still , okay ?
Yeah . Yeah , old school , like Billy and Stu .
Come on , baby , get it up !
Come on . Shoulder me ! Shoulder me ! Shoulder me !
Get it up ! ( grunts ) ( Sidney gasps )
What ? ( gasps )
The heart ... that 's not the way we rehearsed it .
You said it , Charlie : Billy and Stu , Trevor and you .
What the media really loves , baby , ( Charlie gasping )
is a SOLE survivor . ( Charlie gasping )
Just ask you-know-who . ( Charlie gasping )
Trevor was your partner ,
but you , you were the idea man .
( Jill grunts ) ( Charlie gasps ) ( Sid gasps )
( Charlie continues gasping )
( inhales ) Even your friends . ( exhales )
My friends ?
What world are you living in ?
I don 't need friends .
I need fans .
Don 't you get it ?
This has never been about killing you .
It 's about ... becoming you .
I mean , for fuck 's sake , my own mother had to die ...
no great loss there , so I could stay TRUE to the original .
That 's sick , right ?
Well , sick is the new sane .
You had your fifteen minutes .
Now I want mine !
I mean , what am I supposed to do ?
Go to college ? Grad school ? Work ?
Look around .
We all live in public now , we 're all on the Internet .
How do you think people become famous anymore ?
You don 't have to achieve anything .
You just gotta have fucked-up shit happen to you .
So , you do have to die , Sid .
Those are the rules . New movie , new franchise .
There 's only room for one lead , and let 's face it ,
your ingйnue days , they 're over .
( Jill snorts ) ( Sidney gasps )
( orgasmic gasp / sigh )
Don 't tell me you didn 't know this day would come .
( Sidney gasps )
( sighs )
( thud )
( forced rapid breathing )
( slash ) ( grunts )
( ripping )
Aah !
( grunts )
( ripping ) OW !
( cry of pain )
( inhales )
( breathing hard )
( slice ) ( Jill screams )
( slash ) ( gasps )
Oh , fuck !
( panting )
( glass breaking ) ( grunts )
( grunts )
( grunting )
Eeeh ! ( exhales )
( panting )
( grunts )
( grunts ) ( breaking glass )
( groans )
( sighs )
( sirens approaching )
( grunts )
( multiple sirens very close )
Come on , let 's move it !
( siren winds down to silence )
Check the rooms , both sides and upstairs .
( mixture of sirens , police radios , chatter )
( cameras clicking ) Jill , can you give us a description of the murderer ?
( multiple reporters shouting questions )
( woman ) Jill , how does it feel to be a hero ?
( gasps )
Jill , you made it , that 's all that matters .
Trevor , Charlie , they tried to kill me .
And I heard they killed my mom .
And Robbie and Kirby , too .
Shh . Just lay back .
Try to rest .
( exhales ) Is ... is your wife ...
( chuckles softly )
She 's gonna be fine . She 's recovering .
If I ever write a book one day , I 'd - - I 'd want her to write it with me .
We 'd be a good team with our matching wounds and all .
We 're survivors now .
( voice breaking ) I just wish Sidney was , too .
Jill ...
they 're not sure yet .
It 's still touch and go .
But she 's in ICU .
And they think Sidney just might make it .
What ?
But - - but I saw Trevor kill her .
Look , we don 't know yet .
But she 's hanging on .
I - - I - - I wanna see her .
She 's not awake yet .
And she may not remember anything .
You 'll to help her with that .
It 's all in time . Just get some rest now , okay ?
( regular beep of infusion pump )
( infusion pump alarm )
( musical tension building )
She gonna be okay ?
Yeah . She 's a strong kid .
She 's gonna have to be .
( chuckles ) She asked if you were okay .
She thinks you guys should write a book together
with your matching wounds ( chuckles )
Why ? She was stabbed in the shoulder ?
How did she know I was , too ?
Shit !
( breathes deeply )
You just won 't die , will you ?
- ( gasps ) - Who are you ?
Michael fucking Myers ?
Yeah , I don 't think so .
( grunts )
Fucking die already ! ( grunts )
( gasps )
Aagh ! Aah !
( breaking glass )
( grunts )
Augh !
( hoarse screams )
( hoarse scream )
( thud ) ( gasps )
( gasps )
( punch ) ( gasps )
How are those stitches ?
( hoarse scream )
Aaugh ! ( breaking glass )
( Dewey yelling in distance ) : Sidney !
Hicks , get up to Sidney Prescott 's room and call for back-up !
( over radio ) Be right up , sir !
Sid !
- Sid - - - Dewey !
( grunts ) ( repeated bang of bedpan )
( grunts ) ( pan rings from impact )
( safety clicks ) ( chambers bullet )
( exhales )
( breathing heavily ) Is this how it 's gonna be , Sid ?
The ending of the movie was supposed to be at the house .
I mean , this is just ... silly ! ( chuckles )
( gasps ) Consider this an alternate ending .
You 're never gonna get out of this , Jill .
- Of course I will . - ( Gale ) Dewey !
( gasps ) Sid ?
Easy . Okay , wait .
What about the book ?
Looks like I 'll just have to write it myself .
Eee-yah !
( gunshot ) ( cartridge clicks on floor )
- God damn it ! - Ohhh !
Don 't even think about shooting , or I 'll blow Dewey 's head off .
( gasps )
What you think I won 't do it ?
Gimme your gun ! - ( Gale whispers ) Do it !
You just had to be the hero , huh ?
( safety clicks ) Give me ... your gun !
What are you , deaf ?
Give me your gun !
( hits floor )
( scrapes along floor )
And get up .
And keep your hands over your head .
Don 't do anything stu - - ( gunshot ) ( grunts )
Don 't fucking tell me what to do .
( softly ) Oh , God .
Now get up , bitch .
Okay .
Get up !
- Now ! - Okay .
( gasps )
Come on .
( groaning )
Let 's go .
Get your skinny ass out here .
Okay .
( click ) ( machine charging ) I 'm gonna enjoy blowing your head off .
( machine still charging ) Okay , but can I just
have one final word ?
What ? " Please " ?
No .
- Clear . - " Clear " ?
Clear . ( zap )
( thud ) ( broken glass )
You forgot the first rule of remakes , Jill .
Don 't fuck with the original .
( breathing heavily )
Oh , my God , Dewey !
( groans ) What hit me ?
Don 't ask . ( groans )
You okay ?
She was standing right behind me .
They always are .
( broken glass )
( gunshot ) ( gasps )
( all sigh )
Oh , God .
Nice one .
Hicks ? You 're alive ?
Wear the vest , save your chest .
( thud )
( click ) We got two officers down . Several injuries .
And a new suspect . ( click )
( exhales )
We need a doctor , goddamn it !
I don 't know about you , but I feel a whole lot better . ( sighs )
( woman ) We 're live at Woodsboro Community Hospital ,
awaiting a first public statement from Jill Roberts , survivor .
- - A survivor of what is now being called ' The Woodsboro Massacre Re-boot . '
- - Jill Roberts is her name , a name the whole world will now know .
- - who single-handedly put a stop
to this 21st-Century Woodsboro killing spree .
- - Jill Roberts of Woodsboro ,
a girl who 's lifted all our spirits tonight ,
an American hero , right out of the movies .
♪ ( " Bad Karma " plays ) ♪
♪ You better believe in karma
♪ Baby , it 's gonna sting
♪ The wheel of life 's gonna do you in
♪ So I really don 't have to do a thing
♪ You made me drink the Kool-Aid
♪ You tricked me into thinkin ' that Jill means Jack
♪ You are the firstborn of the Devil
♪ But even he ain 't takin ' you back , back , yeah
♪ Bad karma
♪ Oh ! Yeah !
♪ Baby , that 's what you got
♪ Bad karma
♪ Oh ! Yeah !
♪ Whether you believe it or not
♪ The universe is gonna getcha
♪ You 'll be scratchin ' the seven-year itch
♪ You know what I think ?
♪ Bad karma 's a bitch
♪ Ba da da da da-da da-da
♪ Ba-da da da da da
♪ You better believe in karma
♪ Just look at the sorry shape you 're in
♪ There 's a doll with your name and your gloomy face
♪ At the department of doing a rush on your case
♪ You better believe in voodoo , babe
♪ I got a long list of your sins
♪ There 's a word you might have heard called payback
♪ And I 'm runnin ' out of pins
♪ Bad karma
♪ Oh ! Yeah !
♪ Baby , that 's what you got
♪ Bad karma
♪ Oh ! Yeah !
♪ Whether you believe it or not
♪ The universe is gonna getcha
♪ You 'll be scratchin ' the seven-year itch
♪ You know what I think ?
♪ Yeah , bad karma 's a bitch
♪ Ba da da da da-da da-da
♪ Ba-da da da da da Bad karma 's a bitch
♪ Ba-da da da da da
♪ ( " On Fire and Out of Control " plays ) ♪
♪ I don 't have no sympathy , girl
♪ That 's the last you 're giving , I 'm sure
♪ All the time I 'm trying to
♪ Be the man you want me to
♪ But all I ever get from you is silence
♪ Silence
♪ I 'm on fire
♪ Out of control
♪ And out of contro-o-l
♪ Just stop me now
♪ Somebody stop me now
♪ S-s-stop me now
♪ Don 't stop me now
♪ D-d-d-d-don 't stop ... don 't stop ... aah
♪ I 'm on fire
♪ Out of control
♪ Well , I 'm on fire
♪ Baby , I 'm on fire
♪ And out of contro-o-o-l
♪ ( " Run For Your Life " plays ) ♪
♪ And morning comes with a meltdown
♪ This town is needing a shakedown
♪ We 've been burning bridges for hours
♪ Guided by higher powers
♪ And rising up from the edges
♪ This land is covered with faces
♪ We 've been praying for someone to lead us
♪ The end of those who deceive us
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ If I was you
♪ I would run for your life
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ If I was you
♪ I would run for your life
♪ Her face is in every paper
♪ And may we never forget her
♪ A nation cries together
♪ Hoping to remember
♪ Look back at roads we have taken
♪ As sleeping giants awaken
♪ Wasting days till tomorrow
♪ We 'll beg , steal and borrow
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ If I was you
♪ I would run for your life
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ If I was you
♪ I would run for your life
♪ It 's not time to stand in line
♪ If you want to change this
♪ They 'll make the world you measure by
♪ If you let them take you
♪ And hand you to the darker side
♪ So everything 's about you
♪ It 's not time to stand in line
♪ Someone has to change this
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ If I was you
♪ I would run for your life
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ If I was you
♪ I would run for your life
♪ ( " Say Hi " plays ) ♪
♪ Well , the devil got my number
♪ And the devil got my size
♪ And the devil got my head
♪ And the devil got my eyes
♪ I 'm tryin ' hard to get up
♪ Lest he make it to my heart
♪ ' Cause I wanna make it back
♪ From the dark , dark , dark
♪ Aha-ha , yeah , and aha-ha , yeah
♪ Well , aha-ha , yeah , and aha-ha , yeah
♪ Aha-ha , yeah , and aha
♪ It used to be
♪ It was just my house
♪ And it used to be
♪ It was just my tongue
♪ But the devil 's caught on
♪ Like the teeth of a shark
♪ And I wanna make it make it back
♪ From the dark , dark , dark
♪ Oh , woe is me indeed
♪ And a woe is me indeed
♪ And woe is me indeed
♪ Oh , woe is me indeed
♪ And a woe is me indeed
♪ Oh , woe is me indeed and woe
♪ See , the devil got my address
♪ See , the devil got my car
♪ And the devil ain 't no novice
♪ And the devil ain 't no liar
♪ I 'm tryin ' hard to get up
♪ But he made it to my heart
♪ So I cannot make it back
♪ From the dark , dark
♪ Dark
♪ ... .